A Sand...
（うずまきナルト）砂の…
What does this mean?
（はたけカカシ）どういうことです？
I don't know either...
（チヨ）わしにも分からん
But...he went missing right around
the time Gaara was taken.
（チヨ）ただ こヤツは
我愛羅があらが連れ去られる前後から
行方知れずになっておった
（春野はるのサクラ･ナルト）あっ
（サクラ）もしかして
暁あかつきのスパイだったのかも
Could it be that...
he was a spy for the Akatsuki?
I don't believe it.
（チヨ）まさか…
He served on the council
for four years...
４年も上役を務めた こヤツがなあ
Was he disguised with
the Transformation Jutsu?
（ロック･リー）変化へんげの術で
化けていたんでしょうか？
No.
（日向ひゅうがネジ）いや…
そんなレベルの術ではない
This is a Jutsu of
a much greater level...
The Fire Ball Jutsu was created
by the Uchiha Clan
（カカシ）豪火球ごうかきゅうの術は...
うちは一族が編み出した術で
好んでよく使う
and they use it a lot by preference...
（うちはイタチ）火遁(かとん) 豪火球の術
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu.
And that Jutsu was the real thing.
（カカシ）そして あの術は本物だった
It looks like you're done as well.
（干柿ほしがき鬼鮫きさめ）そちらも
終わったようですね
Yes... I'm out of Chakra...
（イタチ）ああ チャクラ切れだ
（鬼鮫）まあ
いけにえに与えたチャクラも...
Well, the Chakra we sacrificed
was only about thirty percent...
３割程度でしたしね
Although it's a Jutsu handy
for creating exact duplicates of us,
私たちの同一体を作り出す
便利な術とはいえ
the quantity of Chakra
we gave them wasn't that much.
切り渡したチャクラの分量は
大したことないですからね
And the Jutsu they can use
are proportionate to that quantity.
それに比例して
力も使える術も限られてくる
But it was more than enough
to buy us time.
（イタチ）だが
足止めは もう十分だろう
The Jutsu wore off, huh...?
（暁のリーダー）術がとけたか
However, we were able
to buy quite a bit of time...
しかし かなりの時間稼ぎはできた
This should be enough...
これなら十分だ
Well done, Itachi, Kisame.
よくやった イタチ 鬼鮫
（サソリ）簡単に言ってくれる
That's easy to say.
The two who became sacrifices
あんたの術の いけにえになって
ヤツらに体を捧げたのは
and gave up their bodies
for your Jutsu...
２人とも俺の部下だってのに
were both my subordinates.
（暁のリーダー）フッ
You should be
the one thanking me...
逆に感謝して
もらいたいぐらいだが
With my Impersonation Jutsu,
２人とも この俺の象転しょうてんの術で
they were both able to become
members of the Akatsuki,
少しの間でも
暁のメンバーになれたんだ
although only for a short time.
（我愛羅のうめき声）
（暁のリーダー）フフッ そろそろか
It's almost time...
♪～
～♪
The Secret of Jinchuriki
（テンテン）
まいったわね
Damn it! This means the real one
is in the hideout, huh...?
本物はアジトってわけね
I guess we can say his goal was
to stall us and to gather information.
（ネジ）こいつの目的は
俺たちの足止めと
情報収集といったところか
Now that we know that,
there's no point in hanging around here.
（リー）そうと分かれば
長居は無用ですね
All right! Let's hurry!
（マイト･ガイ）よし 急ぐぞ
This way!
（パックン）こっちじゃ
Just as I thought...
（チヨ）思ったとおりじゃの
They were clearly stalling for time...
これは明らかな時間稼ぎ
They've sure got a good Jutsu...
（カカシ）
いい術 持ってやがるね ヤツら
I never realized...you were...
fighting against people like this, Naruto.
（サクラ）私の知らない間に… ナルト
あんたは こんなヤツらを
相手にしてきたの
（チヨ）こんな術まで使って
足止めをかけにきたということは…
Using a Jutsu like this
to stall us means...
they're undoubtedly already
extracting the Tailed Beast!
間違いない
ヤツらは すでに尾獣びじゅうを
引き剥がしにかかっとる
（サクラ･ナルト）あっ
We don't have time.
We must save Gaara right away.
（カカシ）時間がないですね
早く我愛羅君を助けねば
- E-Excuse me...
- Hm?
（サクラ）あ… あの…
（カカシ）ん？
What do you mean...
extract the Tailed Beast...?
（サクラ）尾獣を引き剥がすって？
恐らく ヤツら…
It's likely that they're intention is
一尾の守鶴しゅかくで
新たな人柱力じんちゅうりきを作るつもりじゃ
to create a new Jinchuriki
using the One-Tail, Shukaku.
Jinchuriki...?
人柱力？
（ナルト）ん…
I explained before
how the Tailed Beasts possess
説明したな？
尾獣は人柱を超えた力を
持っておると
a power beyond
human comprehension, didn't I?
そして各国は
それを軍事利用しようとしたと
And how each land attempted
to use them as military weapons.
The Jinchuriki...
is what you might call...
人柱力とは いわば
その力をコントロールする存在じゃ
the one who controls that power.
あっ でも さっきは…
But earlier you said...
The Tailed Beasts have
immense Chakra,
尾獣は ばく大なチャクラの塊で
and in the world of Ninja were
used for military purposes
忍界大戦期には
各国 隠れ里が軍事利用しようと
by Hidden Villages around the world.
They competed to
get their hands on them.
競って手に入れようとしたものじゃ
しかし 人柱を超えた
その力を制御することなど
But none was able to control that power
which had surpassed human intelligence.
誰にもできなんだ
In the end, that is...
結果的にはな…
But in the past, there were those
who attempted to control that power.
じゃが かつて人は
その力をコントロール
しようとしたのじゃ
They attempted to control
the Tailed Beast...
尾獣を人に封印することでな
by sealing it inside people.
（サクラ･ナルト）ああっ
そうすることで
尾獣の強すぎる力を抑え込み
By doing so,
they tried to suppress
the extreme power of the Tailed Beast
and then control that power.
その力を支配しようとした
And the ones with the Tailed Beast
sealed within them...
そして尾獣を封印されたもの
in other words, people like Gaara
were called the Jinchuriki.
つまり我愛羅のようなものを
人柱力と呼んだのじゃ
（ナルト）くっ…
（チヨ）人柱力は尾獣と共鳴し
信じられぬ力を使えるのが特徴じゃ
The striking feature of the Jinchuriki is
how it utilizes unbelievable power
by resonating with the "Tailed Beast."
Including Gaara, there have been
three Jinchuriki in the history of the Sand.
砂の歴史には
これまで我愛羅を含め
３人の人柱力が出現した
頼むぞ
I'm counting on you.
So wars were fought often
using the Jinchuriki?
その人柱力を使って
何度も戦争したのね
That's right.
そうじゃ
それじゃあ 人柱力にされた人は？
Then, the people who've
been turned into a Jinchuriki...
あっ…
How can the Tailed Beast be extracted?
どうやれば…
その尾獣を取り出せるんですか？
What's required is
a Sealing Jutsu with the ability...
瞬間的にでも
尾獣の力と釣り合うだけの
効力を発揮する封印術と
to instantaneously balance
the power of the Tailed Beast,
in addition to plenty of time.
かなりの時間を要する
But if that's done, the Jinchuriki...
だが それをしてしまえば
人柱力を…
Don't tell me...
まさか…
That's right...
そうじゃ
尾獣を抜かれた人柱力は…
The Jinchuriki that has
his Tailed Beast extracted...
dies.
死ぬ
The two people I mentioned earlier...
さっき言った２人
我愛羅以外の砂の人柱力は
The Sand Jinchuriki other than Gaara
both had the Shukaku
within them extracted...
いずれも体内より守鶴を抜かれ
and died as a result.
それが原因で死んだ
You're sentimental as always, huh?
Sakura...
（ナルト）相変わらず
涙もろいんだな サクラちゃん
はあっ
Don't worry.
（ナルト）心配すんなって
I'll be saving Gaara!
（ナルト）我愛羅は俺が助けっから
フッ
I-I was concerned...about your...!
私は…
（サクラ）ナルト あんたの…
（ナルト）急ぐってばよ
Let's hurry.
Naruto...
（サクラ）ナルト…
It's from Big Sister, huh...?
（エビゾウ）ねえちゃんからか
（カンクロウ）うっ うう…
（バキ）おおっ
（カンクロウ）うっ…
（バキ）おお
You shouldn't be moving yet.
まだ動くんじゃない 体に障る
It's not good for you in
your condition.
I'm okay.
大丈夫
I can at least walk...
歩くだけなら どうってことねえ
More importantly, it seems we've
been contacted by Granny Chiyo.
それよりもチヨバア様から
連絡が入ったそうじゃん
I can't just lie around!
じっとしてられるか
I see... So you've heard, huh?
そうか お前の耳にも入っていたか
As it happens, we've learned
something terrible from her message.
実はチヨ様からの連絡で
大変なことが分かった
ああ？
Yura was a spy?!
（砂の里の忍）由良(ゆうら)がスパイだと？
I can't believe it...
信じられん
上役を４年も務めた男が…
A man who served on the council
for four years wouldn't...
But...now it makes sense.
だが これでつじつまは合う
How the enemy broke through
the village defenses that easily.
里の守りがどうして
ああも あっさり破られたのか
And I'm sure nobody imagined
よもや警備責任者が
敵のスパイだとは…
a man in charge of security
would be an enemy spy.
誰も予想していなかった
だろうからな
チッ…
Here I thought we had thoroughly
checked everyone out
我愛羅が風影になるときに
全員の身元は
徹底的に洗ったはずなのによ
when Gaara became the Kazekage!
The person in question might've
just been controlled by some kind of Jutsu.
（エビゾウ）おそらく当人は
何かしらの術により
操られとったに過ぎぬのじゃろう
More importantly,
それより これには
肝心なことが書いとらんではないか
it doesn't say anything about
the most crucial thing!
When's the Kazekage coming back?!
いつになったら
我愛羅は帰ってくるんだ
５大国の風影ともあろうものが
Having the Kazekage of one
of the Five Great Shinobi Lands no less
kidnapped by some bandits sets
a bad example for the other lands!
野伏せリの類に
さらわれたとあっては
他国に示しがつかぬぞ
それにじゃ 相手の１人は
And it seems one of them
is Sasori of the Red Sand!
あの赤砂のサソリ
ということじゃないか
It'll be a tremendous disgrace
if this gets out to the other lands!
他国に知れたら
恥さらしもいいとこじゃ
If it becomes known that
the Kazekage is missing,
風影の行方不明が知れれば
who knows when
the neighboring lands will intervene.
近隣諸国がまた
いつ干渉してくるかも分からぬ
Our most pressing need is
to immediately elect a new Kazekage...
ここは新たな風影を
すぐにでも選出し
里の安定のために
努めるのが急務だ
and make an effort to stabilize the village.
まだ我愛羅が帰ってこないと
決まったわけではない
Gaara could still very well come back!
Well, the fact is...
まあ 帰ってこぬほうが
it might just be better for the village
if he doesn't come back.
里にとって都合がいい
というのも事実だが
何が言いたいのです？
What're you getting at?
Gaara is an unstable monster
with the One-Tail inside him.
我愛羅は 一尾を宿しておる
不安定な化けものだ
We thought he would be easier
to control if we made him the Kazekage...
風影に祭り上げれば
ヤツをコントロールしやすい
とは思ったが
But in the end, there's no telling
when he might go out of control.
所詮 いつ
また暴走するやも知れぬ
There's no mistaking he's trouble.
厄介なものには間違いない
Gaara originally resonated with
the One-Tail, Shukaku.
元々 我愛羅は
一尾 守鶴と共鳴こそしたが
But he's an unstable experiment
we can hardly call complete...
完全とは言えぬ
不安定な実験体じゃ
And he's a failed creation who
was even once ordered for assassination
かつて父である４代目みずから...
暗殺の命めいまで下した
失敗作でもある
by his own father, the Fourth Kazekage.
Right now, some of the younger people
just blindly admire him.
今の若い連中の中には
何も知らず
我愛羅を尊敬する者もいるが
But the fact is most of the people
in this village are just scared of him...
この里のほとんどの者は
ただ恐れ
and have no expectations of him!
何も期待など
しておらぬのも事実だ
（足音）
（砂の里の忍）んん？
（カンクロウ）えいっ それ以上
くだらねえこと言ってみろ！
Just try talking trash like that again!
I don't care if you are  on the council.
I won't allow it!
上役とはいえ許さねえぞ！
んんっ んん…
やめろ カンクロウ
Stop, Kankuro!
You're before the statues
of the Kazekage!
風影様たちの石像の前だ
ここは神聖な場所だぞ
This is a holy place!
（カンクロウ）くっ…
カンクロウよ
Kankuro, your anger is understandable.
お前の怒りも最もじゃが
そヤツの言うことにも 一理ある
But there's an element of truth
to what he says.
But the fact is...
ただ 事態は
this isn't an issue of whether
or not Gaara should be trusted.
我愛羅を信頼するしないの
問題ではないのだ
（カンクロウ）チッ
（砂の里の忍）ああっ
ゴホッ ゴホッ
Something like this happened
before a long time ago...
昔 これと同じことがあった
The Third Kazekage was kidnapped.
３代目風影がさらわれたのだ
There were all kinds of conjecture
そのときは
その３代目の所在を巡り
in regards to the whereabouts
of the Third Kazekage,
様々な憶測が流れ
戦争が起き 国々が荒れた
war broke out and the lands
were in chaos...
If only we paid our attention
towards securing the village,
３代目捜しに躍起にならず
里の平定に目を向ければ
rather than eagerly searching
for the Third Kazekage,
that wouldn't have happened.
そうはならなかった
Then why didn't you do that...?
ならなぜ そうしなかった？
The Third Kazekage was
an exceptionally powerful Kazekage
３代目風影は歴代の中でも
ずば抜けて強かった
in our history.
And most importantly,
a body was never found.
そして何より
死体が出てこなかった
あっ…
No one thought someone as powerful as
he could have been killed that easily.
あれほどの方が
そう簡単にやられるはずがないと
誰しもが思ってしまったのだ
Something like that must
never happen again!
あのようなことは
二度と起こしてはならんのだ
That's why...we must consider
the best interests of the village!
だから とにかく今は里を
いちばんに考えるべきなのだ
それで国境の警備を…
So that's why the borders
are being secured...
The village plunged into chaos
前は３代目捜しに
奔走している隙を突かれて
when the enemy broke through
our border by seizing the opportunity
while we were engaged in
the search for the Third Kazekage.
一気に国境を破られ
里は大混乱に陥った
Our most pressing need is
to secure the borders.
国境を固めるのは急務だ
But there was no reason to go out
of your way to send Temari...!
けど 何もわざわざ
テマリでなくても
Kankuro...
カンクロウ
What're you saying?!
何を言う！
Originally we were going to have
you  take on that mission as well!
本来ならお前にも
その任についてもらおうと
思ったのだぞ
But then you get yourself poisoned...!
それを毒などにやられよって
んん…
If we assign Gaara's siblings
to border patrol missions,
我愛羅の兄弟がそろって
国境警備の任についておれば
the young people won't start talking
about nonsense like rescuing Gaara.
若い連中も風影奪還などと
バカげたことを
言い出さぬだろうからな
くっ…
テマリが派遣されたのは
Temari was dispatched to a place
that's been infiltrated by
the enemy many times in the past.
以前にも何度か
敵の侵入を許した場所だ
We needed someone of Jonin rank
or higher to go.
どうしても上忍じょうにん以上の忍が
出向く必要があるのだ
くっ…
I know... But...
分かってる
けどよ… けど…
But...
Gaara's...
我愛羅… 我愛羅は…
my little brother.
俺の弟じゃん
Zetsu.
（暁のリーダー）ゼツ
象転の術に使った２人を
処理しておけ
Dispose of the two we used for
the Impersonation Jutsu.
Understood.
（ゼツ）分かった
Itachi, tell me about the enemy's
number and their features.
（暁のリーダー）イタチ
ヤツらの人数と特徴を教えろ
（イタチ）木こノ葉はの
はたけカカシ 春野サクラ
They're a four-man squad with
Kakashi Hatake, Sakura Haruno,
and the Nine-Tail Jinchuriki
Naruto Uzumaki from the Leaf,
九尾の人柱力 うずまきナルト
and Chiyo, the Sand's advisor.
それに砂の相談役
チヨのフォーマンセルだ
（サソリ）んんっ チヨバアだと？
Did he say Granny Chiyo...?
ハア ハア…
（カカシ）まだ十分に
大玉(おおだま)螺旋丸(らせんがん)を使うのには
It seems he's still not quite accustomed
to using the Giant Rasengan...
慣れてないようだな
あっ ああ…
（パックン）さすがに
景門(けいもん)まで開いただけあって
It looks like opening the Gate of Joy
has left him quite exhausted...
疲労が残ってるようだな
Are you okay, Guy Sensei?
（リー）ガイ先生 大丈夫ですか？
え？
What do you mean?
なんのことだ？
俺は いつも元気いっぱいだぞ
ハハハハハッ
あ～ いっ…
（リー）ガイ先生！
（テンテン）全然 大丈夫じゃない！
無理もない
朝孔雀あさくじゃくを使った直後だ
どこかで休んだほうがいいな
（テマリ）あそこだ
（マツリ）
本当にこんなところを警備して
意味があるのですか？
（テマリ）命令は命令だ
これより
24時間交代で警備にあたる
（４人）はっ！
（カカシ）止まれ！
（ナルト）どうしたんだってばよ？
カカシ先生
（カカシ）ここでしばらく休憩をとる
（ナルト）えっ？
賢明な判断じゃな
（ナルト）んっ…
なんでだよ？
時間がないって言ったのは
カカシ先生じゃねえか
こんなところで休憩なんかしてたら
我愛羅が…
（カカシ）イタチの偽物と
遭遇する前に比べて
明らかにペースが落ちている
えっ…
確かに そのとおりだわ
（カカシ）ここで休憩して
疲れをとったほうが
最終的に目的地に早く着くはずだ
それに あしたは
我愛羅を連れ去ったヤツと
やりあうことになるかもしれない
んん…
（カカシ）体調は
万全にしといたほうがいい
分かったってばよ
（黒ゼツ）こっちが鬼鮫のほうか
処理しがいがありそうだ
（白ゼツ）さっさと処理しようよ
（黒ゼツ）ああ
♪～
～♪
さあ 休憩を挟みまして
再スタートを切りました両チーム
Ａ地点から出発したカカシ班
Ｂ地点から出発したガイ班
共に ただ１つのゴールを
目指します
ええ… なんと言いましても あの…
カカシ選手はガイ選手の
永遠のライバルですからね
こりゃ目が離せません
“絶対に勝ってみせる”との
ガイ選手のコメントが印象的でした
現在の両者のゴールまでの距離は
ほぼ互角で
果たして
この過酷なるレースを制し
勝利の栄光をつかみ取るのは
どちらなのか？
固唾を飲んで
見守っていきたいと思います
次回
「我愛羅死す！」
（ナルト）木ノ葉 観光協会
きょうはテマリとカンクロウを
木ノ葉の温泉街にご案内
ここが源泉地
ここから お風呂屋さんに
温泉がひかれていくんだ
ここの お湯は
めっちゃくちゃ熱いから
気をつけろよ
昔 ここで修業して
ひでえ目にあったんだよ
（カンクロウ）
いいから早く温泉入ろうぜ
（ナルト）うん ちょっと待てって
ああ～ いい湯じゃん
（テマリ）カンクロウ
（カンクロウ）はっ？
（テマリ）石けん 貸してくれ
（カンクロウ）んだよ 忘れたのか？
ダハハ～ しょうがねえなあ
そっちに持ってってやる…
（テマリ）のぞくな！
（ナルト）ああ いた…
（テマリ）ああ
やっぱり温泉は最高だね
ああ まったくだ
今度 砂隠れにも
砂風呂 作ろうぜ
砂風呂ねえ
（我愛羅）砂瀑柩さばくきゅう
いや やめておこう